JOTHI ARUL PRAKASH PONNUSAMI

Security Analyst

jothiarulprakash@gmail.com | 427, Creek Crossing RD NE, Vienna, VA, 22180 | +1(571)-327-7788 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jothiarulprakash

SUMMARY

Highly motivated Security Analyst experienced in detecting and securing information with a capability of working with various types of networks and skilled in auditing the security controls to ensure the organization policies are compliant with the security standards.

EDUCATION

George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia

May 2020

Master's in Information Security and Assurance

Anna University, India Apr 2018

Bachelor's in Computer Science and Engineering

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, George Mason University

Aug 2019 - May 2020

- Handling online and in-class lecture sessions in security for high school students.
- Mentoring students by conducting hands-on activities in security management.
- Evaluating assignments and awarding grades based on the performance.
- Monitoring academic progress of students and assisting in development.

Operations Officer, Blockchain at Mason

Jan 2020 - May 2020

- Managing and analyzing projects of multiple domains.
- Participated in the 'Youth Engineering Conference 2020' to present fundamentals of blockchain.
- Organizing meetups with peer students to discuss upcoming events and connecting with blockchain professionals for research and development.
- Framed a common curriculum for training students from different specialization.

Associate Software Engineer, Accenture, India

Apr 2018 - July 2018

- Developed and managed projects based on web application and security.
- Tested the functionalities of web application modules and their connectivity to ensure a secure connection and dynamic storage of data.
- Improvising project development and management strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming : C, Java, Python, JavaScript, Shell Scripting.

Tools: Splunk, Metasploit, VMWare, Burp Suite, Eclipse, Wireshark, MySQL, Microsoft Office.Technology: Blockchain, Network Protocols, Firewall Configuration, Cryptographic Algorithms, IAM – SSO, USB Forensics.

Standards & Frameworks : PCI-DSS, HIPAA, SOX, RMF, NIST 800-53, ISO 27001.

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

Application Development

- Secured Tourism App for Ministry of Tourism, India to facilitate tourists using Android and Google Firebase.
- Secured cloud-based data sensing model to measure electricity consumption with real-time data using Google Firebase and Arduino platform.
- Secured multi-player web application game with SSL/TLS implementation, Password hashing, Game data encryption, CSRF and XSS Protection to enhance the confidentiality and integrity of players and game availability.

Malware Analysis

• Static and Dynamic Analysis of WannaCry Ransomware with a simulation of propagation and key management using the cryptographic model and a real-time demonstration.

Academic Research

- Blockchain implementation in IoT Devices for secure and protected communication.
- Novel Intrusion Detection System implementation in a Drone network to detect various risk factors that can influence the network.
- Participated in MIT COVID-19: Beat the Pandemic Challenge- I & II to propose a decentralized news verification platform using Blockchain and County-based risk management application to prevent public from fake news related to COVID-19.